in this video I want to investigate
whether I can make this particular
piecewise function continuous everywhere
well I have a little bit of freedom
notice that there's a see inside of
there so the hope is that by
manipulating the C I can make it
continuous everywhere first I want to
note this but look at this function here
or this function individually like if
this applied for all values of X either
of those are just polynomials one's a
quadratic one's a linear and polynomials
are continuous absolutely everywhere
there's no division by zero there's no
infinite spikes there's no oscillatory
behavior these are continuous everywhere
so the only possibility the only spot
where there could be a problem with this
value of x equal to one that's where it
might be that the limit from the left
and I'll limit from the right and the
function value might be different okay
so let's match them our goal is this I
want to say that the limit as X goes to
the interesting spot the 1 as X goes to
1 from let's do the left first of f of X
what I'm hoping is that this is going to
be the same thing as the limit as X goes
to 1 now from the right of my function f
of X so I need that to be the case if I
have any hope for it to be continuous
and an indeed my third condition is that
I want it to be equal to F of 1 that
one's going to come more or less for
free ok well now let's do the one from
the left now from the left is this top
one up here X values less than one so in
other words this is the same thing as
the limit as X goes to 1 from the left
of see x squared plus 1 and and this one
over here is just going to be equal to
the limit as X goes to one now from the
right of 2 X minus C and the F of 1 is
just going to be plugging in here this
is going to be equal to 2 minus C so
these are the three different things
that I need to be equal ok well how do i
do these limits both of these limits
over here are easy in the sense that
these are polynomials so that
ulis so the computer limit I just plug
it in so in this case if I plug in one
for the value of X so this is equal to
two minus C the same value as the
function value as we would have expected
and then over here I'm gonna plug in one
and I'm gonna get c plus one so this
gives me an equation it tells me that I
want C plus one to equal to minus C so
let's do that we're gonna see plus 1 to
be equal to two minus C and then if I do
a little bit of manipulation on this
okay I'm gonna move this C over and this
one I'm gonna subtract off so I'm gonna
have a two C is equal to one and so
finally I have C equal to the value of
one half
and indeed when I do this this value of
C would have hat it fixes the potential
discontinuity at one the letter from the
left is equal to limit from the right so
yes indeed this is continuous at one and
because of continuous everywhere else as
they're polynomials it's continuous
everywhere